Andrew Simons

Front-End Developer Phoenix, AZ <u>simdrew07@gmail.com</u> 512-944-9351 GitHub
LinkedIn
Personal website

Driven Front End Developer with 8 months of experience developing and architecting web applications, specializing in JavaScript and React. Prior experience working as an Order Processing Manager for 5 years, managing day to day operations, sales, quality assurance, and ensuring outstanding customer service.

Work experience

Web Developer at Leap to Success January 2022 - May 2022 (part time)

- Updated and managed website content for Summer Wonders summer camp using Wordpress.
- Constructed and designed registration forms for each grade and session.
- Implemented plugins to manage payment for successful registration using Stripe.
- Designed custom CSS rules to create consistent, elegant, page layouts.
- Collaborated with project manager and clients to implement discussed changes in a timely manner.

Front End Developer at Zollege May 2021 - August 2021 (part time)

- Implemented websites and landing pages from concept through deployment, collaborating with team members, to complete projects on time.
- Designed and managed restaurant front end application that sends reservation requests to server.
- Constructed UX and UI designs.
- Collaborated with product managers to implement new features including animations,
- Establish hosting and deployment for client's applications.
- Maintain web applications using JavaScript and other technologies to find bugs and fix them promptly.

Order Processing Manager at 360 Home Connect 2018 - present

- Lead weekly meetings with sales and QA departments using excellent presentation and organizational skills to encourage a cooperative work environment focused on achieving goals.
- Achieved our 2021 goal of successfully assisting over 1000 clients per month on average.
- Resolve sales consultant business operational issues
- CRM training with sales consultants
- Interview and hire candidates for order support and sales consultant positions
- Collect monthly reports and analyze sales through OPUS to CRM
- Update business rules and automation processes in CRM
- Maintain vendor relationships and contracts / negotiate contracts with vendor partners to sell products at competitive rates.

Sales Representative at 360 Home Connect 2016 - 2018

As sales consultant I was responsible for handling 100-120 clients per month making 30-50 outbound phone calls per day.

- Strong product knowledge of various home services including electricity, water, gas, tv, and internet
- Executed on warm leads, leading to a close rate of 30%, which exceeded expectations and quota of 23%
- Averaged \$75,000 in annual sales over 24 months
- Met or exceeded all quotas, resulting in 70% revenue increase over 24 months.
- Scheduled and organized sales calls
- Excellent written and verbal communication with team members and clients.
- Provided exceptional customer service and client issue resolution.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Business Administration

Delta State University

Certifications

Austin Coding Academy Bootcamp (2019-2020)
Udemy - The Modern Javascript Bootcamp (certification)

Tech Skills and Competencies

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ECMAScript, npm, Node.js, MongoDB, SQL, MERN stack, React, Redux, Git, GitHub, Firebase, Bootstrap, OOP, Agile, API, RESTful API, Algorithms, AJAX

Product Knowledge, Verbal communication, Organization, Time Management, Critical thinking, Leadership, Cold Calling, Customer retention, Consulting, Scheduling, Networking, Data Analysis